ILONA OSTAPCHUK Product Designer

experience

Freelance / Upwork UI/UX & Product designer

Aug 2019 - Present

- Designing web-based and native mobile applications
- Developing wireframes (low & high fidelity), storyboards, mock-ups, user flows
- Creating graphics, banners, and icons
- Creating design systems
- Gathering requirements, defining constraints and user needs
- Regular communication with US and EU clients and team members
- Ensuring smooth functional delivery with front-end and back-end developers

SOFTSERVE Senior QC Engineer Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

- Maintaining manual software testing: Functional Testing, Usability, UI
- Preparing project documentation: Business/Functional Requirements, Use Cases
- Collaborating with developers, UI/UX designers, product team, and stakeholders

CODEMOTION QA Engineer

Mar 2017 - Aug 2018

- Providing software testing of web applications: Functional, GUI/Usability testing, etc.
- Coordinating up to 3 medium-size web projects simultaneously
- Leading demo presentations for clients

CUSTOMERTIMES CORP QA Engineer Nov 2015 - Mar 2017

- Developing and maintaining user acceptance and full regression test scenarios
- Communicating requirements with product management, development, designers, and business analysts

email: ilona.ostapchuk1@gmail.com skype: your_hope999

portfolio

ilonaostapchuk.github.io

about

I have a mix of experience in design, software development, and marketing and I'm ready to share my knowledge and ideas. I'm looking forward to working with intelligent, inspiring, and hard-working people.

skills

Design Research
Information Architecture
Wireframing
Prototyping
User Interface
Responsive Web Design
Mobile App Design
Guidelines for IOS & Android
User-centered design

Figma
Sketch & Zeplin
Adobe XD
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator

Empathy
Communication
Collaboration

education

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB) The Certified Tester in Software Testing

EPAM Systems
Frontend Training
HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Kyiv National University of Trade and Economics Bachelor's degree in Marketing